Jacob Lawrence and Gwendolyn Knight
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings, circa 1973-1995, Series 3:; (Box 5-6; 6 folders)
  Found in this series are published and unpublished writings by Jacob Lawrence such as drafts of speeches, handwritten notes, published essays about his art, and scraps of paper with mailing addresses for friends and colleagues. Other writings include published and unpublished essays, book reports and articles on Lawrence as well as an MA thesis from the University of Wyoming on the paintings of Jacob Lawrence. In addition, a copy of a visitor comment book for the Los Angeles County Museum of Art’s exhibition of Lawrence’s Harriet Tubman and Frederick Douglass series is also found.
  Lists found in this series record a variety of information including artwork by Lawrence published in various books or catalogs, works featured in exhibitions or sold by the Francine Seders or Terry Dintenfass Galleries. Lists also record artworks lent on consignment and include typed or handwritten lists of addresses most likely compiled for invitations to exhibition openings.
  - Handwritten Notes, 1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - LACMA Exhibition Comment Book (copy), 1993, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
  - Writings by Jacob Lawrence, 1973, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Writings by Others, 1973-1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Lists, 1995, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Printed Material, circa 1945-1995, Series 4:; (Boxes 6-9; 3.8 linear feet)
  This series includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs, press releases, programs, brochures, books on Jacob Lawrence, a 1946 book on the Mexican artist Jose Guadalupe Posada that includes an introduction by Diego Rivera, magazines, post card reproductions of Lawrence’s artwork, business cards, art and literary journals including Black Orpheus (Nigeria) and miscellaneous material.
  - Books, 1946-1991, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 4-8)
    Posada: Monografia de 406 grabados de Jose Guadalupe Posada, 1946
    Jacob Lawrence, The American Federation of Arts, 1957
    Jacob Lawrence, Milton W. Brown, 1960
    Woodworking Tools at Shelbourne Museum, F. H. Wildung, 1974
    Jacob Lawrence: American Painter, E. H. Wheat, 1986
    The Frederic Douglass and Harriet Tubman Series, 1938-1940, E. H. Wheat, 1991
    Stories, Philip Yenawine, 1991
    Jacob Lawrence: American Scenes, American Struggles (working copy), M. S. Howard, undated
  - Books of Poetry, 1948-1972, 1991, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Brochures, 1965-1996, undated, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Business Cards, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1945, 1961-1990, (7 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-19)
  - Event Programs, 1949, 1969-1992, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Event Announcements and Invitations (not exhibitions), 1964, 1979-1995, undated, (Not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1962-1995, undated, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1953, 1965-1996, undated, (10 folders; partially scanned) (Box 7, Folder 7-16)
  - Journals, 1947-1991, undated, (6 folders; partially scanned) (Box 8, Folder 1-6)
  - Magazines, 1945-1995, (8 folders; partially scanned) (Box 8, Folder 7-14)
  - Merchandise Catalogs, 1970-1995, undated, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Newsletters, 1965-1995, (2 folders; partially scanned) (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
  - Press Releases, 1960, 1972, 1979-1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Printed Material, Miscellaneous, 1952, 1971, 1979, 1985-1995, undated, (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
- Photographs, circa 1986-1991, Series 5:; (Box 9, OV 10; 3 folders)
  - Photographs of Artwork by J. Lawrence and His Seattle Studio, undated, (Partially scanned) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of J. Lawrence, Gwendolyn Knight and Others, 1987, 1991, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Photographs and Slides of Artwork by J. Lawrence and Others, 1986-1991, undated, (See also OV 10; not scanned) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Oversized Photographs, undated, (2 folders; see also box 9, folder 10) (Box OV 10)
- Financial and Business Files, 1962-1992, Series 6:; (Box 9; 7 folders)
  One financial ledger is for business transactions with the Detroit Institute of Arts (Detroit), Francine Seders Gallery (Seattle), Howard University (Washington, DC), National Urban League (New York), Terry Dintenfass Gallery (New York) and others. Information found includes a record of works lent on consignment, monies received, prices, gallery commissions and other transactions including Lawrence and Knight’s travel expenses for business trips around the country. Business and financial material includes financial statements and consignment and shipping receipts for the Terry Dintenfass Gallery.
  - Ledger and Other Financial Material, 1970-1988 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Terry Dintenfass Gallery Consignment Receipts, 1965-1978 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Terry Dintenfass Gallery Financial Statements, 1962-1986, (4 folders) (Box 9, Folder 13-16)
  - Terry Dintenfass Gallery Shipping Receipts, 1968, 1971-1979, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Original Artwork, 1984, undated, Series 7:; (Box 9; 1 folder)
  - Two Lithographs by artist James Rosenquist, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)